[ Cheering ]
[欢呼声]
[ Applause ]
[掌声]
&gt;&gt; Good afternoon, everyone, and
&gt;&gt; 大家下午好
welcome to modern user
欢迎来到
interaction on iOS.
iOS 现代用户交互的展示
My name is Dominik Wagner.
我叫 Dominik Wagner
I'm an engineer on the UIkit
我是名工程师
frameworks team and I am going
来自 UIkit 框架团队
to talk today about mastering
我今天想跟大家说说
the UIkit's gesture recognizer
如何熟练操作
system.
手势识别系统
I will be joined by my
稍后我的同事
colleagues, Glen and Michael
Glen 和 Michael
later on.
也会上台进行展示
So what are we going to talk
我们要讲的
about?
到底是什么呢
We are going to talk about
我们讲的是
multi-touch.
Multi-Touch
Really just touch interface at
这次只讲
this time.
触摸界面
We have great other ways of
我们有许多很棒的
interacting with the system but
其他交互方式
multi-touch is the subject of
但 Multi-Touch
this talk.
是今天展示的主题
I will talk you through the UI
我会详细地和你们分享
gesture recognizer system in
UI 手势识别系统的方方面面
depth, showing you how to
告诉你们
interact with it and to
如何使用
customize it to your liking.
如何根据喜好进行自定义
Glen will come up and talk to
之后 Glen 会上台和你们分享
you about the new APIs for
iOS 11 中
system gesture interaction in
为系统手势交互而产生的
iOS 11.
New API 的使用
And finally Mike will come up
最后 Mike 会上台
and tell you how to play nice
和你们分享
with the new interactions for
如何玩转
drag and drop.
拖放新功能
So this talk works best if you
这次的展示更适合
already know about how touch is
已经对 UITouch
handled in UIkit.
有所了解的观众
However, if you're new to the
但如果你是新手
system, let's walk over the two
我们就先一起
building blocks for this.
过一遍基础部分
We have the UI touch.
我们有 UITouch
The UI touch is a representation
UITouch 代表
of a finger touching the screen.
手指触摸屏幕
So UI moves from begin, why I
用户交互的状态会从 Begin 开始
move to cancel, or end it, and
以 Cancel 或 Ended 的状态结束
represents one interaction with
它代表一次
the screen.
与屏幕的交互行为
And on top of that we have
另外我们有
UIGestureRecognizer, a more
UIGestureRecognizer
powerful abstraction.
这是个更强大的抽象类
configured with a target and
能配置对象和动作
action and put on a UI view.
放上 UI 视图
And we have gesture recognizer
我们有可以识别各种交互手势的
for all sorts of common
手势识别器
interactions, tap, pan, and
轻点 拖移
pinch.
双指开合
And we have the gesture
我们还有
recognizer system actually
协调这些功能的
coordinating between those.
手势识别系统
And that's what I will be
我接下来
focusing about.
会重点讨论它
And I will do this using a
我会通过这个简单的例子
simple example.
进行说明
Like the AssistiveTouch widget.
跟 AssistiveTouch 一样
You have a widget that it
这个窗口部件
recognizes a tap and you can pan
你可以点
it around.
也可以拖动
And maybe you even do regular
甚至你可以在上面进行
responder based touch handling
常规的基于响应器的触摸处理
on it to pass through some
来处理一些
touches.
触摸
So this example is very simple
这个例子很简单
and purposefully so.
容易实现
I don't want you to think about
你们不用只想着
this example in particular.
这个例子
I want you to think about your
你们可以想想
gesture setups.
你们的手势设置
So where the secrets of
我想说
[inaudible] I'm explaining is
开发触摸事件的秘诀
fitting in your setups and how
在于要适用于你的设置
you can improve yours.
然后再想如何优化你的设置
So let's go through this
那我们来看看
example.
这个例子
We have a view and we have the
这里有一个视图
responder based touch handling
然后还有能在视图上
implemented on the view.
进行的基于响应器的触摸处理
And also we begin with one tap
然后我们从这个
gesture recognizer.
轻点手势识别器开始
So when a touch goes down on
当视图上受到触摸时
this view, it begins in its
它会即刻随其状态开始
state began.
而开始
And the first thing that happens
首先
is the gesture recognizer system
手势识别系统
is delivering it to all gesture
会将其分发给
recognizers interested in that
所有与这个触摸相关的
touch.
手势识别器
That means the tap gesture
在这里就是
recognizer in our case.
轻点手势识别器
And the tap gesture recognizer
然后轻点手势识别器
takes the touch and keeps its
会接管这个触摸
state in its initial state that
并尽量让它保持在
it's possible.
初始状态
And by receiving the touch, it
触摸被接收后
will be marked as being
会被标记为
including in this interaction.
属于此交互
And after the gesture recognizer
手势识别器开始运行后
have their go we move on and
我们继续
deliver that touch into this
将触摸的状态
state, to the touch handling
分发给
methods.
触摸事件处理方法
And when we lift up again, then
触摸的手指抬起来后
the touch moves its state to end
触摸状态结束
it and will be delivered again
依然会在第一时间
first to the gesture recognizer
分发给
system.
手势识别系统
And the tap gesture recognizer
这里的轻点手势识别器
in this case will recognize by
会通过设置状态结束
setting its state to end.
进行识别
This is how your gesture
手势识别器
recognizers signal that they
会用这种方式
recognize.
示意识别
They move their state.
它们会改变它们的状态
And the gesture recognizer
接着手势识别系统
system, in turn, will now take
会接收到标记的状态
this marked state and send out
然后给轻点手势识别器
the action for this tap gesture
发送
recognizer.
动作指令
And after that, we continue
在这之后
onward with sending the UITouch
我们继续向触摸事件处理方法
to the touch handling methods.
发送这个触摸事件
The responder based one.
Responder 类的这个
And as you notice we send it
你们会发现我们发送的状态
onwards as cancelled and not as
是取消
ended.
而不是终止
So why do we do that?
为什么要这么做呢
That is because gesture
这是因为
recognizers hate the regular
手势识别器
touch handling methods, and you
不喜欢常规的触摸处理方法
have wasted influence set.
这会限制它的功能
So there are three properties on
在手势识别器上
your gesture recognizer that you
你可以对三个属性控件
can set and the first two are
进行设置
delaysTouchesEnded and
前两个分别是 delaysTouchesEnded
cancelsTouchesInView.
和 cancelsTouchesInView
Both of them are set to true as
这两个都设置
default and lead to the behavior
默认为 true
we just saw.
从而发生了我们刚看到的动作
That you deliver the touch as
手势识别器识别之后
cancelled if a gesture
触摸分发
recognizer recognizes.
要取消
And you have a third one that is
第三个控件是
delaysTouchesBegan.
delaysTouchesBegan
And if you turn that to a yes
如果对这个控件选了 yes
then the regular responder based
那么即便手势识别了
handling will not even see the
常规的基于响应器的触摸处理
touch if your gesture
都不会看到
recognizes.
触摸事件
So the takeaway here is that the
所以记住
gesture recognizer system comes
触摸分发过程中最先反应的
first in touch delivery.
是手势识别系统
That means that it's one of the
这也是为什么
many reasons why you should move
当在执行触摸事件处理方法时
on to actually implement gesture
你要继续执行
recognizers or use our system
手势识别器
gesture recognizer whereas
或是
implementing the touch handling
使用我们的
methods.
手势识别系统
And only if you need to, you
只有在有必要的时候
should implement them.
你才执行它们
So let's expand on our example
我们拓展一下我们的例子
and add another recognizer to
再加一个识别器
make it a little bit more
给我们
interesting.
增添点趣味
So let's add the pan gesture
我们增加一个
recognizer to this.
拖移手势识别器吧
And again, we follow a touch
同样触摸发生后
sequence of a touch going down.
我们会遵从一个触摸顺序
And it's -- it will be delivered
一开始
as began to all the gesture
它会被分发给
recognizers interested in this.
所有相关的手势识别器
And the gesture recognizers will
然后相应的手势识别器
start out possible and be marked
会立即开始运行并被标记
because they received a touch as
因为系统接收了
interest as part of this
属于此交互
interaction by the system.
触摸事件
And then we will deliver this
然后我们会将这个触摸事件
touch again to the touch
分发给触摸事件处理方法
handling methods and began.
它会开始运行
Now we move the touch.
现在我们移动手指
And if we move the touch, this
手指移动后
is delivered to the gesture and
它会被分发给手势识别系统
the pan gesture, in this case,
然后拖移手势识别器
will recognize because we moved
会因为我们移动了手指
enough that the pan gesture will
对此进行
recognize.
识别
And it will do so by moving its
它会通过将状态改为开启状态
state to began.
来完成识别
However, we didn't move enough
但我们的移动的幅度
for the tap gesture recognizer
不足以让轻点手势识别器
to actually fail.
失效
So we didn't exceed the
我们没有超过
allowable movement.
最大移动范围
So the tap gesture recognizer on
所以轻点手势识别器
its own will stay in the state
会保持原本的
possible.
状态
However, in this case, it still
然而在这个例子中
will fail.
它依然会失效
That is because of another
这跟手势识别系统
aspect of the gesture recognizer
另一个方面
system.
有关
In its default configuration
系统的默认设置中
only gesture recognizer will
只有手势识别器
recognize and win and will
能够识别和成功运行
exclude all the others.
而且是唯一的
And this is what happened here.
这就是现在的情况
And note that the began actually
注意开启状态
will be sent by the gesture
会被手势识别系统发出
recognizer system and the touch
触摸事件处理
handling will be sent as
会以已经取消的状态
cancelled already again because
发出
the pan gesture recognizer
因为拖移手势识别器
cancels touches in view and
取消了视图中的触摸
therefore it began, it will be
所以系统会开启
cancelled which is an
触摸事件处理会取消
interesting thing to look at
这挺有趣的
because your finger is still on
因为你的手指
the screen and the gesture
还在屏幕上
recognizer see it as such but
手势识别器看见了
your responder based handling
但基于响应器的触摸处理
doesn't.
看不见
So that's something to think
你们可以
about.
再想想
And then if you lift the touch,
如果你移开手指
it will move its state to ended.
它就会变成终止状态
And this ended will be delivered
终止状态同样也会
again to the gesture recognizer
最先分发给
system first.
手势识别系统
The pan gesture recognizer will
拖移手势识别器
move its state to ended and mark
会变成终止状态
itself to one -- its action
并标记为
being sent.
动作已发出
And then you might think that
你可能会认为
the tap gesture recognizer will
轻点手势识别器
also see the ended because you
也会看到这个终止状态
usually see all the touch
因为通常
sequences in your handling
你可以在你的处理方法上
methods.
看到全部的触摸顺序
However, because it failed you
但是
don't.
是看不到的
And that's very important if you
这点对于
do your [inaudible] gesture
自定义手势识别器来说
recognizer.
很重要
So whenever your gesture
一旦你的手势识别器无法运作了
recognizer fails, you need to
你需要
reset all your state and make
重置所有状态
sure that you don't leave behind
以确保你没有
old references to touches that
在你还没接收到
you didn't receive an end or
终止或取消的触摸事件上
cancel for.
遗留以前的设置
The ideal place for this is
要操作的位置
reset in your custom, your
在你自定义的重置中
gesture recognizer subtasks.
手势识别器子任务
And then finally the gesture
最后手势识别系统
recognizer system sends out the
会向
ended -- the pan gesture
拖移手势识别器
recognizer action.
发出终止信号
So what you just saw was
你们刚刚看见的就是
exclusion.
Exclusion
This is something that happens
状态变更时
whenever the state change and
会产生这种情况
you have a way to influence
但有种方法
that.
能让你解决
So in your UIGestureRecognizer
UIGestureRecognizer 委托中
delegate you have the method,
有办法让你解决
gesture recognizer should
手势识别器
recognize simultaneously with
应该同步识别
and you can opt in to not be
你可以选择
excluded.
not be excluded 这一选项
Note that this is the only thing
注意你也只能
you can do.
做这件事
If any of the participants wants
所有想要同步识别的参与者
to recognize simultaneously,
都能进行
they will.
同步识别
You have no way to prevent that.
这你无法阻止
And on the UIGestureRecognizer
UIGestureRecognizer 本身
itself, you have the inverse
有 inverse logic
logic which can prevent -- and
可以用来阻止
can prevent it by in your sub
还可以通过子类
classes.
来阻止
So you can do this for gesture
所以你可以把这个
recognizers that you know you
用在你想要
want to recognize simultaneously
进行同步识别的
with.
手势识别器上
So let's see how this looks.
我们看看是怎么回事
So again we have our setup.
同样先是设置
Our touch goes down and began.
触摸屏幕然后进入开启状态
And nothing changed in the
一开始
beginning.
什么都没发生改变
It moves, again, far enough for
移动手指
the pan recognizer to recognize
拖移识别器进行识别
but not far enough for the tap
轻点识别器
recognizer to fail on its own.
无法进行识别
And at this point and time, the
这个时候
gesture recognizer system will
手势识别系统
perform exclusion because state
会因为状态改变
change.
而产生 Exclusion
So the included gesture
属于此交互的手势识别器
recognizers have changed the
改变了
state.
状态
So we ask and this is where the
然后询问问题
delegate callback gets called
得到委托回调
and you return true.
回复 true
And if you return true, the tap
回复 true 之后
gesture recognizer will be
轻点手势识别器
allowed to continue.
会被允许继续运行
And the pan gesture recognizer's
拖移手势识别器的动作
action will be sent.
会被发送
And if you lift the finger now,
如果现在移开手指
the began, the pan gesture
状态开启
recognizer will move to ended
拖移手势识别器
and finish.
会进入终止状态完成工作
And the tap gesture recognizer
轻点手势识别器
will also move to ended and
也会进入终止状态
finish.
完成工作
So it's important to know that
我们需要知道
the gesture recognizers will
手势识别器
change the state before the
会在系统调解前
system actually reconciles them.
改变状态
That means, at this point, the
这意味着在这个时候
gesture recognizer should
系统会再次询问
recognize simultaneously will be
手势识别器是否要同步识别
asked again because we have a
这是因为我们发生了一个状态变更
state change and you still need
如果你想要两个识别器都运行的话
to report true in this delegate
你需要再次在委托方法中
method if you want both to fire.
回复 true
And now that both have
既然两个识别器
recognized, there is another
都进行了识别
thing that's interesting.
这就出现了一个有意思的情况
If you have simultaneous
如果你用
recognition of gesture
手势识别器
recognizers, once the action
进行了同步识别
will be sent, you don't -- you
动作一旦发出
can't rely on a specific order.
你就决定不了顺序了
So the pan and the tap gesture
于是拖移和轻点手势识别器
recognizer will fire because
会不断反馈问题
they're recognized
因为它们同步识别的过程中
simultaneously but you have no
你无法确定
guarantee in which order that
它们会依照
will happen.
什么样的顺序进行
So that's all and well but now
大体来说是好的
we have a little bit of a pan
但现在可能会识别一些
and the tap and maybe that's not
我们并不想要的
what we want.
拖移和轻点动作
If we want the pan recognizer to
如果我们想要拖移识别器
actually wait until the tap
等到轻点识别器
recognizer has exceeded its
超过最大移动范围后
allowable movement, then we have
再进行识别的话
another way to do that and that
我们另有办法
way is called failure
这个方法叫做
requirements.
failure requirements
And failure requirements, you
在 failure requirements 中
can set up between two gesture
你可以对两个手势识别器
recognizers.
进行设置
For example with required to
举个例子
fail statically and this is the
当要求静态失效
preferred one.
并且优先时
And what that means is that one
这意味着
recognizer requires another one
一个识别器要求另一个识别器
to fail before it sends its
在它发送动作前
action.
失效
It still would traverse its
另一个识别器依然会改变状态
state but it waits to send its
但它会等到前一个识别器发送动作后
action.
再改变
And if you need more dynamic and
如果你想要更快捷的操作
one dynamic way to do that you
告诉你个方法
can do so also in the
你也可以在
UIGestureRecognizer delegate
UIGestureRecognizer 委托中输入
with the two methods gesture
两个手势识别器方法
recognizer should require
应该要求为
failure of and gesture
failure of
recognizer should be required to
手势识别器应该要求为
fail by.
fail by
And note that those go both
注意这里
ways.
有两种写法
You need to make sure to agree
你需要确保
in your implementation with what
执行时
your answer here because
你的写法是匹配的
depending on the UI more complex
因为在更复杂的
gesture setup, that might be
UI 手势设置中
called the one way or the other
这个可能叫 one way
way first.
和 the other way first
So that needs to be the same,
所以必须要统一
otherwise, it might lead to
否则可能会
several bugs.
出现 bug
And you have the same in the
UIGestureRecognizer 子类中
UIGestureRecognizer subclasses
也是一样的
where you can implement your
执行
require failure or should be
failure of
required to fail by.
再执行 fail by
Again those directions are more
同样这些指令
for a channel mechanism.
也有其他表述方法
Let's also look into how this
我们再来看看
works.
其中的工作原理
So we have setup our static
我们在
failure requirement between the
拖移手势识别器
pan recognizer and the tap
和轻点手势识别器中间
recognizer.
设置了一个静态 failure requirement
And again, our touch goes down.
再次触摸屏幕
The state start out as possible.
初始状态显示 possible
Then we move the touch.
然后我们移动手指
And the move will be delivered
移动状态会分发给
to both gesture recognizers and
两个手势识别器
the pan recognizer will begin
拖移识别器的状态显示 began
and the tap recognizer will stay
而轻点手势识别器的状态仍然为
possible.
possible
However because the existing
但由于
failure requirement, the pan
failure requirement 的存在
recognizer will not send its
拖移识别器
action at this point and time.
此时不会发送动作
So going on, moving a little bit
接着再往外移一点点
further, but still not far
但又不至于
enough to fail the tap gesture
远到轻点手势识别器无法识别的地步
recognizer we will move, and the
我们移的时候
pan recognizer will change its
拖移识别器会将状态改为
state to changed.
changed
And the tap recognizer will stay
轻点识别器的状态
possible but still the failure
仍然保持为 possible
requirement is not fulfilled.
但 failure requirement 还没完成
So that means still no action.
也就是说仍然无动作
And it is at this point and time
此时此刻
if you would move further away
如果你在往外移一点
then the tap recognizer would
轻点识别器就会失效
fail and by failing would allow
它失效之后
the pan recognizer to send its
就允许了拖移识别器
action.
发送动作
And there's an important message
这里有个很重要的
in there.
信息
If the pan recognizer sends its
如果此时拖移识别器
action as this point and time,
发送了动作
it will send its action in its
它会以 began 的状态
state began.
发送动作
Although it already is in state
虽然它现在的状态是 change
change because we make sure the
但我们要确保
client see a consistent picture
用户看到的是连续的图像
of this but the important part,
重要的是
you should never inspect the
你不能看了
gesture recognizer state outside
手势识别器发送动作时
of its action method and think
显示出的状态后
you know exactly what the state
就误以为是当前的状态
is, because only in the action
因为这个状态只针对
method that is defined.
这个动作方法有效
But now let's go even further
现在我们再进一步
and just lift the touch and the
移开手指
touch then moves into the state
触摸状态显示为 ended
into ended and will be
且即将被
delivered.
分发处理
The pan recognizer move its
拖移识别器的状态更改为 ended
state to ended and recognizes.
并进行识别
The tap gesture recognizer moves
轻点手势识别器的状态
its state into ended and
更改为 ended
recognizes.
并进行识别
But now still no action.
但现在仍然无动作
So we have a complete set of
我们看到拖移手势识别器
state changes in the pan gesture
已经完成了全套的状态变更
recognizer but it never send out
但它还没有发送动作
its action, because the tap
这是因为
recognizer did recognize and
轻点识别器进行了识别
therefore no failure requirement
于是 failure requirement
was fulfilled.
还没结束
And the tap gesture recognizer
轻点手势识别器
will finally send its action.
最后会发送动作
So that is failure requirements.
这就是 failure requirements
Failure requirements really just
Failure requirements 的用处就在于
prevent the extra send of a
阻止一个手势识别器
gesture recognizer.
发送多余动作
And you should be aware of that.
这点你们得知道
Let's look at this picture for a
我们来看看
moment.
这幅图
So this is a regular settings
这是个普通的设定界面
screen and think about how many
想象一下这个屏幕上
gesture recognizers are ready to
有多少手势识别器
drop into action on this screen.
蓄势待发
Just think of a number.
想个数字
Yeah. It is 163.
是的  有 163 个
That sounds quite a lot because
确实是有很多
it is but our gesture recognizer
但我们的手势识别系统
system is built for that and the
就是为此而存在的
way we deal with this is we
我们在做的
narrow that down.
是缩小范围
And for example, if a touch goes
举个例子
down to the -- to this switch
如果点这里  滑动开关
here, we narrowed down the
我们为你
interest gesture recognizers for
缩小了相关手势识别器的
you.
范围
And in this case that leaves
在这个例子中我们减少到了
about seven.
七个
And seven is really a good
只有七个
number to deal with.
就很好处理了
So how do we do this?
这是怎么做到的呢
So in channel, we do hit testing
在 channel 中   我们会在触摸发生时
as soon as a touch goes down.
做命中测试
And this hit testing is done by
命中测试
walking the view hierarchy.
会步步深入视图层级
Starting from window and asking
从窗口开始
the hit testing methods if a
询问命中测试工具
touch is inside of a view.
触摸是否在某个视图中
And when we find the deepest
我们找到最深层的视图后
view, we keep that and assign
我们保存并指定它
that to the touch.
分配给这次触摸事件
And this is a short overview
这是一个
about this.
简要概览
So you have hit test and point
包括了命中测试
inside.
和触摸点
In here this is your override
这是你重载的
points.
触摸点
Note that if you override this
注意如果你重载了触摸点
to extend or contract your hit
来放大或缩小了
testing area, you should
你的命中测试区域
override both of them to agree
你应该两者都
again.
再进行一次重载
Also note that the event in this
还要注意这里的事件
queue is not yet fully formed
是没有完全形成的
because hit test is the first
因为命中测试是我们做的
thing we do.
第一件事
That means that if you inspect
这意味着如果你去检查
the touches of the event, they
事件中的触摸点
might not be there because it's
可能会找不到
really -- we deal with one after
我们需要经过一层一层的测试
another and then add the touches
最后才会把触摸点
to the event.
添加到事件上
So that might be surprising to
也许你会觉得奇怪
you but that's how it is on hit
但在命中测试中
testing.
就是这样的
So the only thing you can ask
对于这个事件
the event is kind of its
你能询问的只有
existence in the callback and
它是否在回调中存在
it's type.
和它的种类
There are more properties that
还有很多属性控件
influence hit testing.
会对命中测试进行影响
For example, in UIView there is
比如 UIView 中的
user interaction is enabled.
isUserInteractionEnabled
This is one of the most
这个是
important ones.
最重要的控件之一
This is usually true other -- if
如果未作更改
you didn't change it but for
它一般默认为 true
example, for an image view that
但有例外  对于图片视图
is false by default.
默认为 false
So you need to switch it to yes
对于这种你需要改为 yes
otherwise you don't have any hit
不然你就无法对此
testing on this one.
进行命中测试
And there's alpha and is hidden
这有个 alpha 和 isHidden
which we use to actually guard
这是用来防护命中测试的
hit testing so if something is
所以对于不可见的东西
invisible we don't hit test it
我们不对它进行命中测试
but in your customs subclasses
但在你的自定义子类中
you really need to also adhere
你还是需要进行
to that.
命中测试
And then there's -- it's
再就是
multiple touch enabled which for
isMultipleTouchEnabled
historical reasons defaults to
出于历史原因默认为 No
no but doesn't affect the
但并不影响
gesture recognizer system.
手势识别系统
So if you ever did come in a
所以如果你
situation where you actually
明明做了双指开合的
have working gesture [inaudible]
相关手势设定
and everything but your
但你的
responder based touch handling
基于响应器的触摸处理
code only ever saw one touch,
只看到了一个触摸
then probably one view in your
很有可能你层级中的一个视图
hierarchy did have set this to
设置成 No
no still.
忘改了
You just need to set this to
你只需要把它
true.
设置为 True
And then, of course, there's
在接下来是
UIViewAnimationOptions when we
UIViewAnimationOptions
default you out of end user
如果你进行了终端用户交互
interaction.
就停止测试
And that's not because we don't
这并不是因为我们不希望
want you to hit test during user
你在用户交互期间
interaction, it's more because
进行命中测试
you really need to do additional
而是如果你授权了
work if you enable this.
你需要再做点额外的工作
So you need to override hit
你需要重载
testing in point and side
内部相关的命中测试
[phonetic] for this to work
从而让它
well.
顺畅运行
And we talked about this in the
我们之前说过
past if presentation layer
表现层和模型层
versus model layer tells you
你应该
something then you're probably
对此
good.
有所收获
If not, please really watch that
如果没有
talk.
请去看看那次展示
And also last year we added the
去年我们新增了
UIViewPropertyAnimator and it
UIViewPropertyAnimator
actually helps you with hit
它可以帮助你
testing during animations.
对动画进行命中测试
However, there is this property
然而对于这个
that is manual hit testing
isManualHitTestingEnabled 的属性控件
enabled and you have to set it
你必须设置为 true
to true to make -- to do custom
从而才能进行自定义命中测试
interesting and more complex
和其他更复杂的
scenarios.
场景
So let's go back to our hit
再回来看
testing in the view hierarchy.
视图层级中的命中测试
Now that we have hit tested.
我们进行了命中测试后
We walk back up the view
我们回来视图层级
hierarchy and collect all the
收集各个视图中
gesture recognizers on those
所有的
views.
手势识别器
This is our base set of gesture
这是我们对这个交互的
recognizers we consider for this
手势识别器基集
interaction but there is more
但还有更多
you can customize on this.
可供你自定义的部分
So you have a callback.
你有个回调函数
UIGestureRecognizer should
UIGestureRecognizer
receive touch.
shouldReceive touch
If you return false from that,
如果你对它返回 false
you can actually exclude a
你就会完全
gesture recognizer from
将一个手势识别器
participating at all.
隔离在外
So it will never see that touch.
它会永远看不见这次触摸
It's also a great break point
这也是个让你
for you to see if your gesture
来看看你的手势识别器
recognizer plays -- gets a
是否真正
chance to actually play with the
参与交互
interaction.
的机会
And there's a point little later
在后面的 gestureRecognizerShouldBegin 上
on that gesture recognizer
也有一个触摸点
should begin also could create
可能会给调试
problem for debugging.
带来问题
And this is asked whenever a
当手势识别器准备开启时
gesture recognizer really tries
会进行询问
to begin and you can say no.
你可以对此说不
False in this case.
也就是返回 False
And if you do so, it will fail.
如果你这样做了  它就会失效
It will not -- it will fulfill
它因为失效
its failure requirements by
会完成 failure requirements
failing and its also a good
这点可以
point to look into.
看看
There's static properties is
这有个 UIGestureRecognizer 上的
enabled on UIGestureRecognizer.
静态属性控件 isEnabled
You can set that to false
如果你知道你的状态
temporarily if you know your
并且想在静态下进行
state and you want to do that
你可以把它设置为 False
statically, that is very
这对你
helpful.
很有帮助
And you also that trick we
这有个技巧
talked about more often that
我们说过很多次了
when you set this to false while
当你设置成 False 时
it recognizes, it will fail.
它在识别时会失效
And if you set it immediately to
如果你立即又设置回 True
true again, your gesture
你的手势识别器
recognizer will begin respond to
就会直接
the next touch sequence
对下一个触摸顺序
directly.
进行回应
And there's the allowed touch
接下来是 allowedTouchTypes
types which default to all the
默认为所有触摸种类
touch types that is direct,
包括直接
indirect, and stylus.
间接和触控笔
But you can narrow it down to
但你也可以
just the stylus or just direct
只选触控笔或直接触摸
touches, but if you really want
但如果你想要
gestures to recognize between
识别不同触摸种类的手势
different touch types you also
你必须把
have to set requires exclusive
requiresExclusiveTouchType
touch type to true.
设置为 True
Only then you can really do a
这样你才能做到
pinch between a pencil and a
用一支铅笔和一根手指
direct touch.
来实现双指开合
Otherwise you can't.
否则是做不到的
Speaking of properties.
说到属性控件
We have new properties for you
我们在 iOS 11 中给你们带来了
in iOS 11.
New Property
And that's a name.
就叫这个名字
Sounds simple but it's really
听起来简单
helpful because we encourage you
但很有帮助
to actually use all of our
因为我们可以让你用
gesture recognizer and just
我们所有的手势识别器
configure them.
并且还能进行配置
So you can add an additional
于是你能添加
name.
附加名称
So in debugging you don't have
调试时你不需要
to look above the action method
去看动作方法
and do that but only use that
你只需要用它来
for debugging.
进行调试就好了
We will not guarantee you that
我们不保证
we will mess with this by the
系统不会对它
system.
进行干涉
And speaking about debugging.
说到调试
We also have the break point
我们现在
opportunities in gesture
取得了一个破发点机会
recognizer should receive touch
可以用手势识别器的 shouldReceive touch
to actually see if your setup
清楚地看到
does work.
你的设置是否生效
There's touches begin
还有这个 touchesBegin
[inaudible] responder base touch
这种 responder base touch handling method
handling method that helps you
可以帮助你
look into the state of a gesture
在已知状态下
recognizer system in a known
检查手势识别器系统的状态
state as you have seen -- you've
你也看到了
seen the order how we do this.
我们操作的步骤
Now you can look into that and
现在你可以对它进行检查
actually know what the values
并且知道各个值的
mean.
意思
And you can look at the gesture
再比如  你还可以看
recognizer of a touch, for
一次触摸的手势识别器
example, or you can look at the
或者你也可以
touches for some gesture
通过询问事件
recognizer by asking the event
来查看触摸的手势识别器
or you can also collect the
你还可以收集
gesture recognizers through the
调试期间
view [inaudible] debugging
所有视图层级的
session.
手势识别器
Some words on custom
再说说
UIGestureRecognizers.
自定义 UIGestureRecognizers.
You should always begin late and
你必须慢开始
fail fast.
快结束
That means if you begin too
就是说如果你过早开始
early, for example, in touches
比如对于触摸事件而言
begin you don't give any other
一旦开始早了
gesture recognizer the chance to
其他手势识别器就没有机会
be not excluded.
设置成 not be excluded 了
This is bad.
这很不好
So you should begin as late as
所以你应该
you can by still preserving the
尽量晚一点开始
intent of your gesture
保证你的手势识别器的
recognizer.
功能
And you also should fail fast so
同时你也要快速结束
you don't hang around failure
免得去影响
requirements of other gesture
其他手势识别器的
recognizers which is very
failure requirements
important and you should also
这点很重要
always whenever you have seen a
你每看到一次触摸事件
touch move to the state to fail
一定要把状态变为fail
even if we didn't move out of
即使是之前的状态一直都是 possible
possible, because you have to be
也要这么做
marked as being part of this
因为你必须被标记为
interaction and otherwise you
属于此交互
hang your system.
否则会使系统中止
Also be serious about ignoring
慎重对待
touches.
屏蔽触摸
Ignore them properly not just by
要正确地去屏蔽
not handling them.
不能只是放在一边不处理
You should also call ignore.
你还应该调用 Ignore
That's for event on your custom
这一步是给
gesture recognizer subclass,
自定义手势识别器子集上的事件做的
otherwise your touches will be
否则你的触摸事件会被延迟
delayed although you weren't
虽然你对它们
even interested in them.
甚至都不感兴趣
And also don't forget touches
永远别忘了
cancelled as always.
设置 touchesCancelled
And this becomes more important
今年这一步变得尤为重要
this year because we cancel
因为我们的拖放功能
touches more often with drag and
会需要更频繁地取消
drop.
触摸事件
So your takeaway from here
在这里你得记住
should be revisit your setups.
要重新访问你的设置
Look into your gesture
好好检查
recognizer setups and try to
手势识别器设置
make sense of the information
好好理顺一下
you've just heard and put them
刚刚听到的知识
together.
归纳好
Revisit your exclusion and
重新访问你的
failure requirements.
exclusion 和 failure requirements
When you use one or the other,
当你在用一个手势识别器时
how many simultaneous gesture
你想要多少个
recognizers do you want to
手势识别器
achieve the same effect?
同步发挥作用
And also are your gesture
你的手势识别器
recognizers on the right views?
是否在正确的视图中
Are they deep enough?
是否够深层
The deeper you move them, the
你放置得越深
less interference is with other
它跟其他手势识别器
gesture recognizers.
产生的干扰越小
The higher you move them the
越是在上层
more general you can make them.
越通用
So you these things you should
所以你得
think about.
好好权衡
And by that, I want to hand over
现在
to Glen for system gesture
我想请 Glen 上台
interaction.
讲讲系统手势交互
Thank you.
谢谢
[ Clapping ]
[掌声]
&gt;&gt; Thanks, Dom.
&gt;&gt; 谢谢 Dom
My name is Glen Low.
我叫 Glen Low
I'm a software engineer with
我是 UIkit
UIkit.
软件工程师
I'm here to tell you about some
我来为大家介绍
brand new API to improve the way
一些全新的
you to interact with the system
能优化系统手势交互体验的
gesture recognizers.
API
But first a little
先来玩个
entertainment.
小游戏
After a hard's day coding, this
辛辛苦苦码一天代码的
software engineer needs to play.
软件工程师想玩玩游戏
So I fire up my demo bots and
所以我打开了 Demobots
move the robot around by
在虚拟控件上
dragging up and down on the
上上下下滑动
virtual controls.
操作机器人
You see it on the upper right of
就是屏幕右上角的
the screen.
这个
The gray circles.
灰色圆圈
And it looks like this.
就像这样
My little robot has to change
我的机器人必须
the bad robots into good robots.
把坏机器人变成好机器人
As you see I'm doing quite well.
你们看我玩得还不错
I think I missed one.
好像错过了一个
I need to get -- I need to go
我得往下走
down to get that one.
找到那个机器人
No oops, what happened?
欸  这是怎么了
I got that new cover sheet
为什么我退回到了
instead?
桌面
That's not quite the user
这不是我们
experience we're looking for
想要营造的
here, is it?
用户体验吧
So what exactly went wrong?
那哪里错了呢
Well, we currently have a few
我们现在有几个
special gestures we call system
特殊的手势
gestures.
我们称作系统手势
You swipe up from the bottom,
从底部向上滑
you get the multitasking and
可以拉出多任务处理栏
dock.
和 Dock 栏
Swiping out from the -- to the
从侧面滑
side brings in the slide over.
可以实现 SlideOver 功能
Swiping it from the top brings
从顶部向下滑
down the cover sheet.
会拉出桌面
Now these special system
现在这些特殊的系统手势识别器
gestures recognizers fight with
会阻碍你 App 中的
your apps own gesture
手势识别器
recognizers and responders to
和响应器
try and get to the touches
意图率先
first.
识别触摸
So what could we do?
那么我们能做些什么呢
Well we do make an exception for
有一些手势识别器
gesture recognizers.
例外
Your tap, pinch, rotate, and
轻点  双指开合  旋转
long press gesture recognizers
和长按手势识别器
can [inaudible] touches at the
能够在系统手势识别器
same time as a system gesture
识别的同时
recognizes.
识别触摸
Although sometimes they will get
但是有些时候
cancelled if it's obvious later
如果发现明显是系统手势
on that it's actually a system
它们也会被
gesture.
取消
That's why just tapping on a
这就是为什么
button at the bottom won't
当你在底部点一个按钮
actually accidentally bring up
并不会拉出
the dock.
Dock 栏的原因
That's because that's based on a
因为它是基于
tap gesture recognizer.
轻点手势识别器的
On the other hand, we have pan
另一方面
and swipe recognizers as well as
我们有拖移和轻扫识别器
your old school responders.
以及早就有的响应器
While these will get the touches
而这些会在
after the system gesture
系统手势识别器识别之后
recognizers are done with them.
对触摸进行处理
So when our users swipe from the
那么当我们的用户
bottom, do you really want to
轻轻滑动了底部的时候
bring up the dock or do he want
他是想打开 Dock 栏呢
to pan your view?
还是拖动视野呢
Well, we had to guess whether to
我们得去猜
defer that system gesture.
是否需要延迟系统手势
For example, if your app
举个例子
happened to hide the status bar,
如果这个 App 隐藏了状态栏
we would defer bringing up the
我们就会延迟
dock but it was hard to guess
上拉 Dock 栏
right all the time.
但要一直猜对是很难的
And really who knows best what
到底谁最清楚
your user wants?
用户想要什么
For iOS 11, you can now tell us
对于 iOS 11  你现在可以告诉我们
when to defer and where to
什么时候延迟
defer.
在哪进行延迟
No more guesses.
不需要再猜
You are not responsible for
你不用再去判断
deciding whether to defer system
是否需要延迟
gestures or not.
系统手势
This means if your app hides the
也就是说
status bar, we don't
如果你的 App 隐藏了状态栏
automatically defer the dock
不会再自动
anymore.
延迟 Dock 栏
What does this look like?
看起来是什么样呢
Instead you need to use this new
你要用到一个新的
API we call ScreenEdgesDeferring
叫做 ScreenEdgesDeferringSystemGestures
System Gestures.
的 API
This API lets you declare which
这个 API 能让你
edges you want us to defer
界定一个范围
system gestures in favor of your
范围内会延迟系统识别器
own gesture recognizers.
从而保护你自己的手势识别器
In your view controllers,
在你的试图控制器中
override preferredScreenEdges
重载
Deferring System Gesutres to
preferredScreenEdgesDeferringSystemGesutres
return the screen edges for
以返回要延迟的
deferring.
屏幕边界
Then whenever you want to return
如果你想返回其他
something different, call
调用
setNeedsUpdateOfScreen Edges
setNeedsUpdateOfScreenEdges
Deferring System Gestures.
DeferringSystemGestures
Let's have a look at what is
我们看看
this referral actually achieves.
这个调用是干嘛的
Now when the user starts off in
当用户触摸界面底部时
the bottom, your gesture
你的手势识别器
recognizers and responders get
和响应器
the touches immediately.
同时得到触摸
At the same time, we show a
这时
tongue [phonetic], or a
我们显示一个拉出箭头
[inaudible] so the user can see
让用户看到
that they can do more.
他们有更多选择
Swiping up from the bottom a
再一次在底部向上滑
second time, then brings up the
就能上拉
dock.
Dock 栏
One more method if you're
如果你都是在
writing it all in container view
容器视图下进行编写的话
controller.
再教你一招
Most of the time this
一般而言
[inaudible] for container view
这个 MyContainerViewController
controller is actually in the
实际上就是
child view controller.
ChildViewController
So you'll want to return the
所以你返回的
right one in your override of
重载得写对
childViewController For Screen
应该是
EdgesDeferring System Gestures
childViewControllerForScreenEdgesDeferringSystemGestures
which, I think, is like the new
它应该有希望拿下
candidate for the longest method
iOS 最长的方法名
name in iOS.
的称号
Now that you have all this power
现在万事俱备
at your fingertips, when should
都在你指之下
you use it?
你该什么时候用呢
The short answer is don't do it.
简而言之  别用
Well why am I here, right?
那我来这干嘛  是吧
The long answer, though, think
不那么简而言之就是
hard and long about when to use
好好思考什么时候用
it and why is that?
为什么
Well number one, your user is
第一
familiar with swiping up to get
你的用户对上拉 Dock 栏的操作
the dock and other system
和其他的系统手势
gestures.
都非常熟悉
So using this API actually
这时用这个 API
breaks the intuition.
会违背他们的习惯
It breaks the expectation of
会跟他们的期望
what actually happens.
相矛盾
Also if you're using tap, pinch,
再者  如果你用的是
rotate, and long press gesture
我们之前说过的
recognizers as we talked about
轻点  双指开合  旋转和长按手势的话
before, you're going to get
你即便不用 API
these touches first anyway
这些触摸也会被
without even touching an API.
率先识别
Third we reserve the right to
第三
ignore or modify the suggested
我们保留屏蔽或修改
edges for deferring.
延迟边界的权利
So don't rely on the system
所以不要总想着
doing exactly what you asked it
系统会完全按照
to do.
你说的去做
And finally this API is for when
如果你是需要
you really expect the user's
用户长时间
full attention interacting the
与全屏幕交互
whole screen for long periods.
才用这个API
For example, if you're writing a
假如你在编写一款游戏
game or drawing apps ask
或者绘图 App 的时候
yourself, is your app really
你问问自己
that immersive enough to use
你的这款 App 是否真正
this API?
需要用到这个 API
So on that note, I'd like to
说到这里
hand you over to my colleague,
有请我的同事
Mike Turner, who will talk to
Mike Turner 上台
you about how to work with drag
他会告诉你们如何使用
and drop.
拖放功能
Mikey?
Mikey
[ Clapping ]
[掌声]
Thanks Glow.
谢谢 Glow
So as you've seen with iOS 11,
大家也看到了  在 iOS 11 中
we have a lot of great new
我们做了许多更新
features and near the top of
首屈一指的
that list is drag and drop.
就是拖放功能
And with drag and drop, the
有了拖放功能
users have an opportunity to
用户可以以一种新鲜有趣的方式
interact with your application
与各位的 App
in exciting new ways.
互动
But there is some things you'll
但你们得了解
need to know about how to best
如何运用你们 App 中现有的
interact with drag and drop with
一些手势识别器
some of the existing gesture
来让拖放功能的效果
recognizers in your application.
最大化
So I'd like to start with a
所以我先做个简单的示例
brief example of showing you how
告诉你们
you can make a view implement
如何在视图中加入拖动功能
drag and then what happens to
以及这么做了之后
your existing gesture
对你现有手势识别器
recognizers when you do so.
会有什么影响
So in iOS 11, we added a new
在 iOS 11 中  我们新增了一个类
class called UIDragInteraction.
叫做 UIDragInteraction
UIDragInteraction is really
UIDragInteraction用起来
super simple to use.
超级简单
It's very familiar.
非常符合习惯
Similar to the pattern of
跟手势识别器的操作
gesture recognizer or adding a
和添加子视图的操作一样
subview to a view and you just
你只要
initialize one of these with a
选择一个委托
delegate of your choice and you
设定初始值
call add interaction on a view.
然后在视图中调用 addInteraction
And that's pretty much all you
做完这些
got to do.
就差不多了
You got to implement one
你设置好了一个委托 API
delegate API and you have drag.
你就有拖动功能了
Really simple.
非常简单
So let's look at a quick
我们来看一个简短的展示
demonstration of what a view
看看你添加了一个拖动交互后
looks like when you add a drag
你的视图
interaction to it.
是什么样
And here we're going to long
我们长按视图这里
press on the view and then move
然后移动
a little bit.
一点点
So when you long press, the view
长按
lifts up off the screen.
视图会悬浮在屏幕上
When you move, it kind of tears
移动的时候
out of your application.
就像撕掉了一样
So let's see how drag
我们再来看看
interaction accomplished this
在你 App 里是如何实现
behavior in your app.
拖动交互的
So when we added the drag
我们新增拖动交互后
interaction, it gets added to a
UIView 上
new interactions array on
出现了新的
UIView.
交互组
And the drag interaction, in
于是拖动交互
turn, creates some gesture
给自己生成了一些
recognizers on its behalf.
手势识别器
Attaches them to your view and
依附在视图上
becomes the delegate of those
并且成为了这些手势识别器的
gesture recognizers.
委托
And it creates gesture
生成的手势识别器
recognizers for initiating the
可以初始化拖动
drag, managing relationships
处理与其他手势识别器的
with other gesture recognizers,
关系
and adding additional items to
并给 App 已有的拖动
an existing drag in the
添加其他
application.
东西
So to make this example a little
更具体一点
bit more concrete, let's add our
我们在视图新增
own UILongPressGestureRecognizer
UILongPressGestureRecognizer
to the view and we'll wire that
有了这个
up to an action that will pop an
会跳出这幅图的
activity view controller up for
一个
this image.
活动视图控制器
So here when we get the gesture
在这里当手势识别器的状态
recognizer state began, we're
为 Began 时
going to present an activity
我们打开这个
view controller and we get the
活动视图控制器
gesture recognizer state cancel,
手势识别器的状态为 Cancel 时
we're going to dismiss that
我们关上
activity view controller.
活动视图控制器
So let's look at that same
我们再回到
example again where we long
这个长按后移动的
press on the view and move.
例子
Now that we have our own
现在我们有了自己的
UILongPressGestureRecognizer
UILongPressGestureRecognizer
alongside.
在里面
So here we long press and move.
长按  移动
And I didn't see any activity
没有出现什么
view controller there.
活动视图控制器
And that's because your long
这是因为
press gesture recognizers are
当有拖动交互时
now delayed when they're
长按手势识别器
alongside a UI drag interaction.
会被延迟
So let's adjust our user
那我们稍微调整一下
interaction a little bit here to
我们的操作
see if we can get the activity
看看能不能把活动视图控制器
view controller to show up.
给弄出来
This time we'll long press and
这一次我们长按后
we'll hold for just a little bit
保持一下
and then we'll move.
再移动
So here we long press, hold, and
长按  保持
So here we saw the activity view
我们看到活动视图控制器
controller briefly and then it
出来了一下
was dismissed.
马上又没了
And that's because a beginning
这是因为一个开始了的拖动
drag will cancel the touch you
会取消
used to begin that drag in your
你 App 里上一个拖动的
application.
触摸
So we'll send touches cancelled
我们会为这次触摸
for that touch to the app.
向 App 发送取消其他触摸
The app will then send it to its
然后 App 会把它发送给
gesture recognizers and
手势识别器
responders.
和响应器
The gesture recognizer will then
于是手势识别器
send the cancelled state to its
会给这个动作
action and thus dismissing that
发送取消的状态
activity view controller.
于是就关闭了这个活动视图控制器
So in a compact trait
在紧凑的界面中
environment, adaptivity will
活动视图控制器
take that presentation of the
会适应屏幕大小
activity view controller and
变成
it'll turn into an action sheet.
一张上拉菜单
So let's see what happens in
我们看看这会是
that case.
什么样
So we'll long press.
所以我们要在
Hold for a bit and then move in
紧凑的界面中
a compact trait environment.
长按并保持一会儿再移动
Here we long press.
长按
Hold and move.
保持  移动
No activity view controller
又没有活动视图
again.
控制器
So let's see what happens here.
来看看是什么情况
Your long presses are being
在这里
delayed until the touch ends in
长按会被一直延迟到触摸结束
this case because in a compact
这是因为
trait environment, most of the
在紧凑的界面中
presentations turn into modal
弹框
presentation styles or action
和上拉菜单
sheets that would cover the
大多都会妨碍
impending drag and that's not a
用户继续拖动
great user experience.
影响用户体验
So let's look at how we can
我们看看
adjust our user interaction here
我们怎么调整一下操作
to get that activity view
让活动视图控制器
controller.
出现
So we'll long press and lift.
我们长按再松开
So we long press and then lift
长按后
the touch.
松开手指
And there you have it.
有了
Your action sheet is up with the
上拉菜单出现了
activity view controller.
活动视图控制器
So UIDragInteraction also has
所以 UIDragInteraction
some built in ability to add
还有能往拖动上添加其他物件的
additional items to a drag and
内置功能
as I said, it creates another
也就是我之前说的
gesture recognizer to perform
通过生成另一个手势识别器
this ability.
来完成
So here, this is a quick
这里很快地
demonstration.
展示一下
We had a long press and move.
我们长按  移动
And then we can tap again on the
再轻点视图
view to add additional items.
添加其他物件
And it handles that tap for you
它会帮你处理这次轻点
but you do have a way of
但你也可以
influencing this.
进行更改
First this is an optional
首先这个动作是
behavior.
非强制的
So the delegate method, items
所以这个添加物件的
for adding to on the
委托方法
UIDragInteraction is optional.
UIDragInteraction 是非强制的
You don't implement, you won't
你不执行
get the adding behavior but if
你就不会有这个添加的行为
you do implement it, you can
但即便你执行了
conditionally return zero items
你也可以返回"return zero items
in this API to continue
in this API to continue"
processing this touch as you
以平常的方式
normally would in your app.
对这个触摸进行处理
So it's really quite simple to
所以使用 UIDragInteraction 时
adapt your application when
适用于你的 App
you're using UIDragInteraction.
并不难
It's pretty much hands off but
基本无需手动操作
you need a few basic concepts to
你只要知道一些
get you the rest of the way.
基本概念就行了
And the first thing you do is
你要做的第一件事
just examine your existing
就只是检验你现有的
actions.
动作
Do they make sense alongside
是否能配合
UIDragInteraction?
UIDragInteraction
In some cases, UIDragInteraction
有些情况  UIDragInteraction
might replace some of that
可能可以取代
existing functionality that you
UILongPress 的
had from a UILongPress.
一些现有功能
And you need to be careful
你在用
presenting modal UI when you
UIDragInteraction
have a long press -- excuse me,
呈现模式用户界面的时候
when you have a
得要
UIDragInteraction.
非常注意
And that's because in a standard
这是因为在标准界面下
trait environment, it's going to
它会被延迟
be delayed and it might end be
而且可能
presenting over top of the drag
在拖动之前展示
and you need to take the
在此你需要
appropriate action here.
注意一下
And then you need to handle the
之后你得处理
cancelled state in your
你 UIGestureRecognizers 中的
UIGestureRecognizers.
Cancel 状态
As you see when the drag begins,
你们之前也看到了  拖动一开始
we send touch is cancelled.
我们发送了触摸已取消
So if you're not handling the
所以如果你不处理
cancelled state in your gesture
你手势识别器的 Cancel 状态的话
recognizer you won't have the
你就无法
opportunity to take the
像我们的示例中那样
appropriate action in our
关闭
example that was dismissing the
活动视图
activity view controller.
控制器了
And you need to remember one
注意关于 UIDragInteraction
really important but super cool
有一点非常重要
part of UIDragInteraction and
也特别酷
that's your app is fully
就是你的 App 在拖动期间
interactive during a drag.
是完全交互的
So you might have some
所以可能会产生
interaction that you wouldn't
一些预想不到的
expect.
交互行为
So you've been warned on that.
你们得警惕
So Dom came up here and told us
Dom 之前上台告诉我们
about how you can best leverage
如何最有好地使用
the gesture recognizer system to
手势识别系统
get the setup that you want and
来进行你想要的设定
how you can use failure
以及如何通过 failure requirements
requirements and exclusion to
和 exclusion
influence how gesture
来处理
recognizers fire with each
若干手势识别器之间的
other.
关系
And he made the important point
他告诉了我们很重要的一点
of the gesture recognizers come
手势识别器是
first.
第一位出现的
So when we send touches through
所以当我们通过
application the gesture
发送触摸时
recognizers can block your
手势识别器会
responder based touch handling.
阻止基于响应器的触摸处理
So you should always attempt to
所以你应该
use gesture recognizers when at
尽一切可能
all possible to get the best
使用手势识别器
results.
来达到目的
And Glen told us how we can use
然后 Glen 告诉我们
the new system gesture deferring
当我们需要滑动屏幕边缘时
APIs to give preference to the
如何运用New系统手势延迟 API
gesture recognizers within our
优先我们 App 中的
application when swiping from
手势
the edges.
识别器
And you should use these very
在全屏的情况下
sparingly, you know, in full
你要非常保守地
screen situations.
使用这个方法
Things where your users are
只有在用户
going to expect interaction in
使用 App 时明确期望发生的交互
your app and not the system
不是系统手势的时候
behavior.
才使用
So very sparingly.
所以用得很少
And finally, we had a brief talk
最后我们简要地说了一下
about how you can adapt your app
如何在你的 App 中
to use UIDragInteraction and
使用 UIDragInteraction
it's really quite simple.
特别简单
So I hope you add
所以我希望你们可以
UIDragInteraction to most of
多多在你们的视图中
your views.
使用 UIDragInteraction
And for more information, you
想了解更多资讯的话
can see the video in replay on
你们可以在这个网站
the following website.
看视频回放
We have some great past sessions
我们做了一些很棒的展示
that go in-depth on handling
深入探讨了 UIkit 中的
events in UIkit.
事件处理方法
If you haven't seen them, I
如果你还没看过
highly would recommend those.
我强烈推荐
And we have some other sessions
我们还会有一些关于
related to drag and drop and
拖放和动画的展示
animations that you should check
你们可以关注一下
out, and have a great WWDC.
好好享受 WWDC 吧
[ Applause ]
[掌声]